it's a cold November with only a thin
scattering of snow and the gray skies
have reflected my own existence lately
the beginning of my pregnancy has left
me absolutely exhausted and after being
a bit frustrated about the sudden Turtle
pace of my life I decided that that
attitude wasn't serving me instead I
decided to accept how I feel and find
joy in this new slowness and see what it
can teach me I've always considered
myself a bit of a slowo person when
things get rushed and chaotic I get all
frazzled a bit like a little field mouse
in a rainstorm the way I've made peace
with this natural disposition has been
to accept a rhythm of living that is far
from the fast lane as
[Music]
possible
I remember years ago describing myself
as always and forever tired I realize
now that I wasn't really tired I just
wasn't living the way that suited me
best it's hard to have energy when you
get yours from a different Source than
someone else might a bird might feed on
seeds to grow while a plant takes in the
Sun and yet they both Thrive when their
needs are met but they are slightly
[Music]
different
you
[Music]
three
[Applause]
[Music]
boy I needed to cultivate within the
pace I was yearing for and for the last
2 weeks I've been trying to stay true to
that and focus on being only as
productive as my body allows I beged a
Thanksgiving treat for my in-laws
decorated the house for the festive
season and started to declutter a bit in
preparation for the baby in the new year
just doing these things while still
working has sucked up all my energy and
I've spent so much time in bed it's been
a humbling experience to be
sure I've spent the last several years
learning how to slow down my my thoughts
my movements adjusting my entire
lifestyle to remind me just because you
can't match the pace of someone else
doesn't mean you're too slow it means
you're listening to the beat of a
different song one that in my case has
been whispering to my soul from the very
day I was born slow down look listen
rest and that couldn't be more true than
it is
now
[Music]
the art of resting actually resting in
my experience isn't about doing
something mindless to make the day pass
by it's about leaning into the awareness
of time stretching it out to make it
serve you better and to honor your
energy your body and listen digging into
the parts of myself that house pain and
insecurities bringing those things to
the surface with gentle words and giving
them the care they have longed for also
helped me feel that much more at peace
with my pace of
life
[Music]
every time you let go a little more of
anything that's holding you back you
feel lighter more rested more whole that
is quality rest it's not always easy
but it teaches you how to surrender
you're not always the one in control and
I think there is freedom in that
[Music]
acceptance
hello everyone as you may know from my
updates recently on Instagram and here I
have uh slowed down drastically between
doctor's appointments and morning
sickness and everything else in between
um I have just had uh the hardest time
staying at the same productivity I did
before
Oh my cat just laid down and put her paw
on my
hand do you want to hold hands okay I'm
okay with that it feels like everything
in my life has slowed down so much as
physically I've had to so I appreciate
your understanding I am perfectly fine I
do find myself you know being a bit more
emotional but that's understandable
considering everything going on but I'm
trying to accept it with Grace and flow
with it and know that it all will lead
to good things I don't know about you
but I definitely felt that I was raised
in a world where you know working really
hard and being extremely productive was
just crucial 24/7 not ever letting life
get in the way of your productivity and
that that was a sign of strength I know
that definitely stems also from from
growing up in a military environment and
I have come to grow and mature with that
mindset and come to understand that the
amount of things that you get done in a
day does not dictate your worth and what
is considered productive is such a
relative term of course I do juggle
several different jobs I am an artist I
also make videos here but I also work at
my local bookstore and so all those
things on a weekly basis have been a bit
overwhelming lately with just having a
hard time just keeping food in my
stomach and just dreaming of sleep and
wanting to sleep 10 hours a day it's
it's amazing thankfully I think my
animals intuitively have understood that
something has shifted and changed
because they also have been honoring
that slowness lately especially my cat
who just loves the heat of the fireplace
and she just can cozy up here with me
practically all day a reminder to all of
you that I know depending on life
circumstances myself included we cannot
always afford to slow down but when
those opportunities come I think that if
we are in a habit of rushing all the
time it's really hard to really embrace
the art of truly resting with that being
said I wanted to share with you all a
story that I wrote in October and I had
this huge grand plan to make an entire
short film showcasing this story life
circumstances and a very very tiny human
changed a lot for me so I ended up not
making that short film and I am sad that
I could not do it but I also am
accepting that it just wasn't possible
under the circumstances and anyhow I
decided that I would share it with you
today and I would just read the story I
will go get it off my bookshelf now cuz
I wrote it down
so I have a little story scribbled down
between the pages of this book and I
wanted to share it with you today the
valley in October bursts with so much
color and beauty and it inspired this
legend of the fox and the fairy child
and I hope that you enjoy it it is a
simple story but hopefully one that
speaks to many today I wanted to tell
you a story it is not a grand Story full
of Dragons and Knights and dangerous
quests it does involve losing something
very important but not in the way you
may think it tells of a grand Journey
but not the type that takes you to the
far reaches of the world this is the
story of a little girl with wild hair
that ever resisted The Taming of a brush
she lived with her family in a cabin
with a Mossy roof and a crooked chimney
she was very loved but like many
thoughtful children she sometimes felt
alone and preferred the company of her
imaginary friends and the fairies that
lived in the wilderness
nearby one day in late October when the
world was cast in Amber and gold she
wandered down a path into the deepest
part of the wood she stopped at the
remains of a great and ancient Oak and
knelt there and whispered kind things to
the tree then she took some Amber and
mud and formed a little figure of a fox
a friendly Fox she decided one that
would be her new best friend she left
the figure at the base of the tree and
went
home the next morning she returned and
was surprised to find a beautiful red
fox kit asleep beneath the gnarled Roots
it did not run from her instead it
approached and gently nuzzled her Palm
the girl was immediately Enchanted and
spent the entire day with the fox they
would play hide and seek Splash in the
nearby Pond and watch the clouds on bare
hillsides
soon the fox and child became
Inseparable eventually when the first
blizzard of winter came the girl was not
able to go to the tree the fox ever
patient snuggled Under The Roots once
again and waited for her the girl would
return in the spring only to find the
fox under the influence of a magical
sleep overgrown with moss and Vines it
was not until Autumn came once again
that it finally awoke and waited for the
girl so pleased to be reunited once
again they spent every day together
until the winter returned this continued
year after year and though the girl Grew
Older the fox did not as her own life
became more complicated she found that
sometimes she was not able to go and
visit the fox sometimes the girl
wouldn't visit for a day or two
sometimes a week sometimes a month and
then one October after many seasons of
shared Memories the girl did not come
and visit the fox at all the fox waited
each day by the base of the old tree but
she never arrived it could not be sure
what kept her away but assumed that now
that she was older she must have left to
seek her fortune and do more important
things so it was happy for her and slept
each October it woke and waited and each
season the girl did not appear the fox
could not be sure how many years passed
it did not keep track of such human
things but it did think that it had
spent much more time sleeping now than
it used to it dreamed of the little girl
and longed for the day it would see her
again in one particularly beautiful
Autumn it
did she was no longer a child in fact
she was now a stooped old woman who
walked slowly and with great care but
her hair was still long and worn loose
and wild and so the fox immediately
recognized her and nuzzled her Palm as
it did when they had first met and they
held each other for a long time lost in
the Bliss of being reunited after a long
absence the old woman shed many tears as
she H the fox I am sorry I've not come
to visit for so long I think without
even realizing I lost something I
couldn't find the right path through the
forest I was preoccupied with my own
troubles and it made the Wilderness look
unfamiliar so I gave up trying to find
you I'm sorry the fox curled up in her
lap and made Happy
sounds the woman caressed its vibrant
coat it was so easy to find find the
PATH now I'm not sure what changed but
I'm glad it did I've been quite lonely
and desperately wanted to come home the
fox placed his soft head in her hands
and she whispered some words into its
ear she then stood up quite erect and
strong like a woman much younger than
herself and removed her shoes and socks
relieved at the feel of the Cool Moss
beneath her toes she took several
confident steps Guided by the fox
together they walked through the woods
and were soon enveloped by the mist and
falling leaves Legend has it that if you
walk through a forest in Autumn at dawn
or dusk when the light is soft and the
air is crisp you may see a little fox
playing beneath the branches of a pine a
Barefoot girl with wild hair is sure to
be near laughing and singing with a
gentle voice that could easily be
mistaken for a passing Breeze if you
pause and listen you may remember that
there's something you too have lost on
your journey and it may be waiting for
you in the woods
and that is the story of The Fox and the
fairy
child I hope you enjoyed that it's
definitely a story that was very special
to me definitely inspired by just the
gorgeous Autumn we've had over here it
is a good reminder to me to listen to my
inner child and stay true to that
essence of what makes me who I am
sending you so much love thank you for
so much support of this channel my work
as an artist on my Etsy Shop it means
the world and I appreciate your
understanding as I go through these
enormous changes in my life and that I
know will affect this channel in some
ways but I am doing my very best to make
videos at the pace I'm able and thank
you so much for being here I'm sending
you a huge hug and so much love
[Music]
goodbye